nmims.edu 2019-04-25

# NMIMS | Top University in India | Leading Business School |Narsee Monjee Institute of Management studies

The NMIMS University (hereby called NMIMS for the purpose of this document) is committed to protect the privacy of individuals who visit the website and who make use of the on-line facilities. To that effect, we have the following privacy policy in place with regard to the collection, use and dissemination of personal information collected by this website. This document will help you understand the terms and conditions under which personal information is provided to this website. Please note that this policy is effective only within NMIMS’s domain, and does not apply to websites that may be accessible from external links provided in various pages of this website. Also note that due to the very nature of internet technology and evolving threats, this policy may be updated from time to time. All such updates will be posted in the privacy policy page. In continuing to use this website, you indicate your acceptance of the terms and policies.

## Information Collection and Use  

While you can use parts of this website without providing any personal information, certain sections will only be accessible after you have registered with the website by providing specific data. These sections include, but are not limited to news feed requests, brochure or video requests, Donations, Registrations, Books, Journals and Alumni Profiles, subscription to mailing lists, alumni profile updates, applications and certain databases. As a general rule, NMIMS will not sell, swap, rent, or otherwise disclose to any third party any such personal information for commercial purposes. Such information will be utilized only for the purpose stated. To accomplish such purpose, NMIMS may disclose the information to its employees, consultants and agents who have a legitimate need to know the information. NMIMS also reserves the right to disclose this information under special circumstances, including disclosures required by law, court order or circumstances under which disclosure, in the sole discretion of NMIMS, is necessary to protect the legal rights, including the intellectual property rights, of NMIMS.

## System Information Including IP Addresses  

When you connect to our website, our web server may record the numerical Internet Protocol (IP) address of the computer you are using, information about your browser and operating system, date and time of access and the internet address and page which linked you to our site. The Institute’s staff uses such information to help diagnose problems with our server, to administer and improve our website and to generate aggregate statistical reports that analyze general user information and demographics. Such extrapolations and statistics may be made public; however, they cannot be tracked to individual users. Unless required by legal process, we do not link IP addresses to anything personally identifiable. This means that user sessions may be tracked by IP address, but a user's identity remains anonymous. 

In addition, we ordinarily do not disclose to third parties site usage by individual IP addresses, but may do so in very limited circumstances when complying with law or legal process, working with consultants assisting us in fixing or improving our site, or in monitoring and improving the security of our network. Our staff monitors search terms that users enter into our Search Engine, but this tracking is never associated with individual users.

## Cookies  

Cookies are unique bits of computer data that many major websites will transfer to your computer the first time that you visit. Cookies are stored on your hard drive and may be later accessed by the website to track prior usage.NMIMS uses cookies for a variety of purposes including authentication and can be blocked by reconfiguring the appropriate settings in your web browser. Doing so may, however, restrict access to certain parts of the website. Cookies can also be removed from the user’s hard drive whenever he wishes through his browser options. Information collected through cookies cannot be traced back to the user as it contains no personally identifiable data like name, address or phone number.

## Online Forms  

The NMIMS website uses online forms where you may be asked to provide certain personal information. This is necessary to access certain services in the website (e.g. registrations) or to take part in surveys. By filling out and submitting the form you are understood to have consented to NMIMS storing and using the information for the purposes for which it has been provided.

## External Links  

The NMIMS site contains links to other independently run Web sites within the NMIMS network and to some sites that are not controlled by NMIMS and are not covered by this privacy policy. Our Web site includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook, Linkedin, Google+ and Twitter icon and Share button or interactive mini-programs that run on our site. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy statement of the company providing it. NMIMS is not responsible for the privacy practices, security or content of such Web sites. 

## Security Precautions  

NMIMS has security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under our control. Unfortunately, due to the nature of Internet communications, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be completely secure. While NMIMS remains committed to protecting the privacy of our users, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us, and you do so at your own risk. Once we receive your transmission, we make our best effort to ensure its security on our systems. We do so by using secure technology, privacy protection controls, and restrictions on employee access, however, we make no representations regarding the veracity of such measures.

## Changes to this privacy policy  

If there are any changes to this privacy policy, NMIMS will replace this page with an updated version. We therefore recommend, that it is in the users interest, to check the "Privacy Policy" page any time the user accesses our web site so as to be aware of any changes which may occur from time to time.

If you have any questions about security on our Web site, you can email us at

privacy.questions@nmims.edu
